Well, it's here. We have Claude Fable
5.1 and Mythos 5.1. They're the world's
most advanced models for coding and
knowledge work. I mean, right now Fable
5 is definitely the most capable model
that I've ever played with, and 5.1 is
apparently much, much better and a
little bit cheaper. Now, when I say
cheaper, I don't mean the input and
output cost. It's the exact same $10 per
million input and $50 per million
output, but it seems to be more
efficient, which ultimately means it
eats less tokens and costs less. And
obviously, it literally just came out,
but it is available right now. You can
see that I've got some running right
here in my desktop app, Fable 5.1, and
I'm just comparing Fable 5.1 and Fable
5. So, trust me, I'm going to have a
video coming out later after I've gotten
time to play with them for a few hours
and see how they feel and see how they
cost. But, you can see we're starting to
get some outputs back, so maybe at the
end of this video I'll compare a few
things. But anyways, right here is the
actual blog, and it looks different. It
looks a little bit different than the
way their blogs typically look. We can
change the color up here. We can change
the the theme, but you'll notice in the
bottom right that it says that this was
made by Fable 5.1. So, already it just
feels a little bit different, and I'm
really interested to see how Fable 5.1
does with design. And you can see right
here at the top, they already say Fable
5.1 will cost an estimated 25% less than
Fable 5 for typical workflows wherever
usage is billed by token. This is
because we're reducing our pricing on
cash reads, where the model reads input
that we've already processed and it
stores it. And for highly agentic work,
the savings will often be much larger,
up to approximately 50% would be insane.
They also have a new EFS system, which
you can read about on the separate page,
which basically lets enterprise
customers opt in to have, you know, no
data retention being stored. It's a
complete privacy policy, which is
obviously great for these enterprises
that are looking to adopt Claude. And
they've also improved the safeguards to
reduce false positives. This is pretty
interesting, too, because literally just
a few hours ago I dropped a video, and
like 12 hours ago they dropped um their
blog on what they were doing with an
older Claude model, basically training
it to be evil, training it to hack. And
so, if you guys haven't seen that video,
I'll tag that right up here. Definitely
check it out. It was an interesting one.
But after they have done all that
research, now they come around and say,
"Oh, by the way, also, here's Fable 5.1,
and we have improved our safeguards to
reduce false positives and making this
stuff more safe." Now, look at this, a
new frontier performance. Now, these
crafts are really interesting. Now,
obviously, take these metrics and take
these benchmarks with a grain of salt.
You have to get in there, see how it
works, but look how much better this is
showing that Fable 5.1 is compared to
Fable 5. Now, not only better on the
effort, like Fable 5.1 on low is better
than the strongest Fable 5 on max or
high or ex-high, and it's cheaper. Right
over here, we can see $11.10,
and over here, we see 44 bucks, or we
see 34 bucks. This is incredible. And if
this is really holds true, then it's
going to get really fun to get in here
and play with Fable 5.1. Same thing on
agentic terminal coding, you can see
that it's very similar pattern as well,
multi-disciplinary reasoning and agentic
coding as well. Even this chart, like
it's nothing crazy, but just the way
that it's designed definitely feels
different than the previous blog posts
of model releases, where they typically
used like Fable 5 to design Fable 5's
release blog and Opus 5 to design Opus
5's release blog. And you know, it
wouldn't be an Anthropic blog model drop
if there wasn't the best GPT model in
here as well, which obviously, in these
benchmarks, it looks like it's crushing
it out of the water. But this is a
massive jump over Fable 5. Like that is
really interesting. Now, we can see
here, Claude Mythos 5.1 is identical to
Fable 5.1, but it offers more permissive
safeguards for vetted individuals and
organizations whose work is affected by
the cybersecurity and life sciences
restrictions outlined above. So, it's
only available, Mythos 5.1 is only
available to two trusted access
programs, the cyber verification program
and the life sciences verification
program. So, if you fit in there, go
ahead and apply. You might as well get
your hands dirty with Mythos 5.1. And
once again, this stuff is available
today. You can see I've got it running
right in here in my Claude desktop app.
You could also be running this, of
course, in the terminal, or I think it
said via API, as well, including Amazon
Web Services, Google Cloud, Microsoft
Azure. Developers can get started with
cloud-fable-5-1
on the cloud API. So, real quick before
I end the video, let's take a look at
these results. We can see here that I've
got Fable that built me a 3D bear. Here
it is. You can see we've got a bear on a
bike. We can move it around. I can click
space to pause. I can click space to
play. It is nothing crazy. Obviously, my
prompt here was literally just, "Hey,
build me a rotating 3D cartoon bear
riding a bike." And you can also see
that Fable 5.1 finished it up. It was
the exact same prompt and it gave me a
live artifact. It also named the bear
Barnaby. Let me open this up real quick.
You can see that we have the bear. I
mean, this obviously looks a bit better.
You can see the other one was a little
bit more colorful, but the actual bear
itself and even kind of the physics
looks a little bit more realistic.
Like I said though, this is not any sort
of like definitive test or benchmark,
but the bear definitely looks better in
this one. There's like the shadows. You
can see the shadows look way more
realistic. The physics feel more real.
Um but that's a super open into prompt.
Now, real quick, what I want to do is do
a  cost and we'll see how much
this one spent. This one costed us um
about 6 minutes, 34 seconds, and $4.53.
If I go back into the Fable 5 version,
we'll do the same thing.  usage.
Shoot that off. This one was $5.41 and
it was a little bit faster. But, already
on a very simple example, Fable 5.1 was
roughly a dollar cheaper for this
example. And I've got these other
experiments running that are going to
take a little longer. I'm going to
design a bunch of websites. I'm going to
try the things and I'll make a video
later basically telling you guys my
findings. But anyways, that is going to
do it for today. So, I hope you guys
enjoyed the video. You learned something
new. Please give it a like. I'll see you
guys in the next one. Thanks, everyone.